

## Full stack developer / Team lead / Solution Architect 10+ years experienced.

Germany, Düsseldorf 40217

Babak.zarrinbal@gmail.com

+49 157 3489 7539

#### **ABOUT ME**

LinkedIn:

https://linkedin.com/in/babak-zarrinbal/

https://npmjs.com/~babak.zarrinbal

GitHub:

https://github.com/babakzarrinbal

https://gitlab.com/bzarrinbal

Experience: 10+ years

Titles: 49 Senior Full stack developer/ Team Lead / Solution Architect / Technical Mng Responsibilities: Proposals / Architecture / Implementations / team building / Mentoring

Domains: Telecom / Commercials / Startups / Insurance / Finance / security

Personality: self-Growing / Team Worker / Energetic / Work is life, it should be fun

Growth comes from within oneself, Truth is the drive for Knowledge,

Anything can be accomplished when people come together.

# **EXPERIENCE AND EXPERTISE:**

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Architecture: Micro-service, Micro-Frontend, Terraform,

CI/CD: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, CircleCI, Kubernetes, Docker, Rancher,

AWS: ECS, EC2, IAM, Lambda, S3, DynamoDB, EKS, VPC, Fargate, API gateway, SAM, CDK

Oracle: OCI, Db, ML,

Azure: VM, Functions, Devops, Blob storage, Transcribing, TTS, Translation API.

Google cloud: Auth, drive API, map API, Document AI, Translation API,

**Platforms** 

**Architecture** 

Linux containerized apps, Web apps, Cloud services, Electron, React Native, Chrome extensions,

Vscode extensions

JavaScript: (12 years), TypeScript: (6 years)

Raw JavaScript/TypeScript, NodeJS, NestJs, NextJS, GraphQL, ReactJS, VueJS, NuxtJS, Svelte,

ExpressJS, FastifyJS, SocketIO, AngularJS & Angular 12, CLI scripts

Languages

Python: (2 years) Django, Transformers,

Java: (1 years) SpringBoot

Golang: (1 year) Gin

Bash: (5 years) as a secondary scripting language

PHP: (4 years but it's old stack now) Laravel, Drupal, WordPress, Joomla

**Database** 

Oracle DB, Mongo dB, Cassandra DB, MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite, SQL Server

**Message Brokers** 

/ Cache

RabbitMQ, Kafka, SNS, SQS, Redis, Memcache

**Monitoring Tools** 

Grafana, Kibana, GitHub Reporting, Jira, Kanban Boards, Teams, Excel, MS Projects, Grant graphs, and a lot of meeting with talented people

#### MOST RECENT CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Since Feb 2022: Fueling Innovation at Retraced: I'm currently spearheading teams at Retraced, an international trailblazer in tracing and sustainability. As a Team Lead, I'm driving groundbreaking solutions that impact global processes. From Node.js services to Oracle databases, I orchestrate diverse technologies to achieve remarkable results.

- Service Proposal / team assembly / architecture design / development / deployment / technical bridge
- Team leading through feature development or maintaining epics
- Hands-on bug fixing, app developing, designing
- · Product meeting to understand needs and strategy going forward
- Performance evaluation, recruiting talents

**2016 - 2022** Tecnotree: Where Innovation Meets Telecom Navigating the intricate landscape of international telecommunications at Tecnotree, I spearheaded a 20-member strong team as a Technical Lead. In this Finnish software powerhouse, I not only pioneered the development of applications that underpin crucial telecom operations but also mentored and guided teams to resounding success. From orchestrating Node.js marvels to seamlessly managing Kubernetes, I ensured our services remained at the forefront of innovation.

- Technical mng. Responsibilities
  - o progress report/ funding meetings / personal evaluation/ top level product strategies
  - o Grooming product needs/ proposing solutions/ discussing implementation ideas
  - Leading 20+ developers into 5 rotating teams,
  - o Performance management / recruitment process
  - o Implementing flat hierarchy to increase innovation and performance
- As senior full-stack developer in early days
  - o Proposed and implemented over 5 full featured services for different parts of the eco system

style has empowered teams, driving excellence in performance, and fostering innovation.

- o Going through the whole ecosystem with different team to further improve the products
- Assembled teams to perform tasks,
- o Bug fixing, test implementation, feature developments, architecture implementation

From **2012** On Ecommerce, Geolocation, Education: My journey began in the dynamic realms of Ecommerce, Geolocation, and Education. In these diverse sectors, I crafted versatile solutions and pioneered novel approaches. My leadership

#### **EDUCATIONS AND SKILLS**

- University: B.A. of Industrial Eng. from University of science and culture (Tehran, Iran)
- Languages:
  - English (Fluent) has been working with international teams since 2008.
  - Persian (Native), my mother tongue
  - German (A2), in process of learning
  - Arabic (basic understanding)
- Project management courses for MBA
- financial management courses

Project planning and control courses

#### Work History

#### Retraced: (since Feb 2022)

As a hands-on **technical manager/team lead** I teach, guide, and work alongside my teammates to reach the goals of the platform which is vary.

technologies included:

- NodeJS micro services services
- React front-end app
- Circleci / github actions, terraform
- Watchdog for production monitoring
- Aws: ECS, EC2, S3, EKS
- Oracle db
- RabbitMQ
- Docker, Kubernetes, Github Actions

#### Tecnotree: (Sep 2016-Feb 2022)

As a **Technical Manager** I've managed 3 teams regarding development and maintenance of multiple (more then 70) services to ensure delivery of 3 main telecommunication projects in here I've managed, created, educated and guided new teams, and implemented the one man do it all approach on all the scenarios and proud to say I have guided almost 10+ people from junior seniority skills Technologies included:

- Nodejs
- Spring boot
- Cassandra, mongo dB, MySQL,
- Kafka, RabbitMQ
- Rancher, docker, Kubernetes
- React, Vue, AngularJS.
- Ci/cd with Jenkins
- AWS, GOOGLE cloud services

#### Diliviri/Eposense: (Sep 2015-Sep 2016)

As **Team Lead and senior full stack** developer I developed and improved existing parts of the whole ecosystem of the Diliviri (app for deliver goods with hired/outsourced driver and vehicles). I added multiple apps as well as improvement in followings ...

- Changed monolithic Admin app to microservice architect (Efficiency +400%)
- Converted Driver & Supervisor Native apps for IOS, Android to PWA apps (Development costs -60%)
- Created complex Multi routing algorithms for concurrent deliveries with one driver (profit avg +50%)
- Kick started standalone routing (in map) and tile Api server for completely free of charge map view and routing (map costs -100%)
- Created CI/CD procedure to ensure code health and faster integration for testing and deployment (DevUp costs 70%)
- Creating/modifying and managing 6 apps under the whole product ...

### • Rahpooyan: (Mar 2013-Sep 2015)

As **full stack** developer I developed and kickstarted and multiple products based on multiple customer needs and descriptions.

- Easybimeh.com (front-end) Improving system for example adding lazy loading and breaking services for better user experience (Efficiency +40%)
- Wow.kanoon.ir (full stack) create and deploy full featured learning app to teach/test and give certificate for English learning (Creating revenue)
- Visit24.ir (full stack) create and deploy 4 different parts whole startup to kickstart it and created the development team and mentored them to continue the work (Creating revenue)
- Review (full stack) creation and deployment of video clip audio extraction and translation plus online subtitle creation (Creating revenue)
- Choqok (full stack) creation and deployment of pdf modification and content adding system for teachers/ reviewers/ experts/ students (Creating revenue)
- Multiple Crawlers for extracting information from different sites and Api for creating datasets and using them in different projects. (Creating revenue)
- Apanajh (front-end) creating front end for Apanajh social media startup and create and mentor front-end team for them ... (Creating revenue)
- Multiple sites and application for various use cases

#### Freelance Jobs /ISIRAN: (2012 to 2013)

A Lot of front-end / full-stack project that I've done in that period mainly done with php/Laravel MySQL and VueJs AngularJs and some with Drupal, and after a while I got hired in ISIRAN and this was my first full time development job

#### Atlas-Offshore, Knauf Iran: (2008 to 2013)

I worked as project planner / controller in mostly gas and oil projects , sometimes as team managers and leaders. I Developed a lot of features and mini apps to perform their tasks and automate them , at some point I developed a whole reporting system that decreased the cost of procedure and man/hour about 50%